Akhmadjon Abdusamadov

Software Engineer



LinkedIn info.ahmadjon@gmail.com +998-97-129-9777 ahmadjon.uz t.me/AkhmadjonAbdusamadov

About Me

I've been coding for over 5 years. I am a software developer who loves building web applications & learning new technologies. I've also helped a number of people learn how to code. I have also conducted technical interviews for newcomers in companies. My interest in programming leads me to study Computer Science deeper. Learning new languages is so much enjoyable as they open new solutions to actual problems and make people's lives easier.

Work Experience (5 years)



React Software Engineer, at Codemotion Ninjas LLC

Codemotion Ninjas LLC provides complex web development for Fintech, Logistics, and Startups

February 2022 to present (1 year)

- Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Identifying web-based user interactions.
- Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components using react concepts.



Software Engineer, at EPAM System

EPAM System is a global job platform offering remote work opportunities for tech professionals. 2021 - 2022 (full-time)

Stack: React, React context API, Typescript

Mentor:

- Mentoring new comers in lab
- · Being technical interviewer

Responsibilities:

- Developed the logic of the front Integrations
- Fixed bugs
- Wrote tests
- Developed a UI Components
- Optimized performance

Project metrics and key features:

- 10000+ simultaneous users
- 2 TB of CDN data
- 1000+ marketing campaigns launched Transactions queue allowing third-party downtime



Full stack developer, at Alitech Website Solutions

Alitech Website Solutions 2019 - 2021 (full-time)

Stack: React, Redux-toolkit, thunk, Nodejs, ExpressJs, MongoDB

Responsibilities:

- Developed the logic of the application
- Designed UI elements
- Created API
- Implemented real-time tracking
- Participated in integration with 3rd party systems (leaflet map and etc) Integration with DB
- Fixed bugs
- Organized and managed operational troubleshooting and performance optimization processes of application



Frontend Developer, at Alitech Website Solutions

Alitech Website Solutions 2018 - 2019 (full-time)

Stack: Typescript, React, Redux,

Responsibilities:

- · Developed the logic of the front
- · Wrote tests
- Fixed bugs
- Implemented authorization for different countries/roles Developed autopay steps
- Developed a UI Components

Hard Skills

- HTML & CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES6...), Typescript, jQuery, React, Redux, Material UI, Antd
- Jest, Enzyme
- Node.js, Express, REST API, Socket.io, WebPack, GraphQL,
- · MongoDB, SQL,
- Firebase
- React Native
- · Figma, Command Line,

Soft Skills

- Ability to analyze complex technical data
- The desire to solve logical problems quickly, master technology quickly, regularly

Education History

Radio devices and networks

Institution: Jizzakh Polytechnic institute Year of Graduation: 2022

- GPA 5
- Mentor Frontend Dev Club
- First Place at Newldea Hackathon among universities

Alicode academy

Web development 2017 - 2018

LinkedIn licenses & certifications

- Create a CRM Mobile Application with React Native
- JavaScript: Best Practices for Functions and Classes
- Node.js: Microservices

Volunteer Work and Affiliations

Mentor

The IT Park of Jizzakh city
2020 to 2021

Every month, I volunteer to teach frontend literacy to children

Language

- Uzbek (Native)
- · English advanced
- Russian elementary